

# Saoirse Mullan Digital Designer



www.saoirsemullan.com



saoirse.mullan79@gmail.com



07565895806



Belfast, N.I



https://www.linkedin.com/in/saoirsemullan/



@saoirsemullan



@saoirsemullan

#### About Me

A designer with a keen interest in User Experience, Interface & Graphic Design.

I'm a confident, highly motivated and creative student determined to succeed in the tech and design Industry. Continuously learning new techniques, software and keeping up with emerging trends. Continuously learning new techniques, software and keeping up with emerging trends. Actively attending UX, Women Tech Space and Digital design meetups in Belfast. I am Graphic & Digital Designer at Ulster University while in my final year of studies, with over 16 months of industry experience.

## Experience

## Graphic & Digital Designer

Ulster University | Belfast | September 2019 - Present

- Edit and design the Ulster University website using Squiz CMS and ensured online content met accessibility guidelines
- Create marketing material such as email banners, social media graphics and brochures and leaflets to be promoted across all university campuses

## Design Intern

Snack At Franks | Belfast | July 2019 - September 2019

- Worked within a start up company to help generate design ideas for promotional purposes
- Produced materials such as flyers and cards for the subscription box
- Developed Graphic Design and illustrative work using Adobe Illustrator, InDesign and Procreate

## Web Design Intern

Ulster University | Jordanstown | September 2018 – July 2019

- Updated, redesigned and redeveloped one key university system; the Employability Portal covering both student and staff view.
- Developed both user and digital experience for employability by updating layouts, graphics and content.
- Optimised front-end efficiency and deployed content management using Squiz and October CMS.
- Designed graphics for web and print promoting career services.
- Designed posters, email graphics, leaflets, flyers and PowerPoint presentations.
- Illustrated designs for instituted wide employability initiative (UU Create-A Enterprise program: including a lanyard, pen, notepad and certificates.)
- Developed an understanding of HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Value of time management to tight deadlines and prioritising workload
- Increased web usability, accessibility and standards.

## **Skills**

#### UX/UI

- Interface Design
- User experience
- Wireframing
- UI prototyping
- User Personas
- User Flows
- User Testing
- Problem Solving

#### Front-end Skills

- HTML5
- CSS4
- JavaScript
- Github
- Bootstrap

#### Software & Technology

- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe InDesign
- Adobe XD
- Microsoft Office

#### Graphic Design

- Typography
- Brand Identity
- Logo Design
- Icon Design
- Illustration

## References

Brian Byers Employability Manager B.byers@ulster.ac.uk 07515570706

Paul McCormack Course Director, Interaction Design, Ulster University p.mccormack@ulster.ac.uk

## Other Work Experience

#### Waitress

- Salt Bistro: May 2018 August 2018
- Malmaison: December 2016 November 2017
- Titanic Belfast: April 2016 November 2016

## **Education & Qualifications**

BSC Hons Interaction Design • Ulster University • 2019 – 2020 Interaction Design at the Belfast School of Art.

- Major Project Prototying
- Research & Writing
- Design Presenation & Reporting

## BSC Hons Interactive Multimedia Design • Ulster University • 2016 - 2020

Completed a three-year undergraduate degree on a high 2:1. Some modules included:

- Dynamic Web Authoring Client View & Server View
- Intro to Communication Design
- Managing Web Platforms and Content

## Level 3 Diploma ICT • Belfast Metropolitan College • 2015 - 2016

Attained a double grade Distinction\* Distinction

## English • University of Dundee • 2014 - 2015

Studied English, Film Studies and Philosophy. Obtained a certificate of Higher Education after receiving a First.

## A Levels • Limavady Grammar School • 2012 - 2014

Art & Design: B

English Literature and Language: B

Politics: D

#### GCSE'S • St Mary's Limavady • 2007 - 2012

10 GCSE'S: C in Maths, B in Additional Maths and a B in English.

## Additional Achievements & Accrediations

- Ulster EDGE Excel Award November 2019
- Womenfolk Mentoring program: May October 2019
- Kainos A.I. Camp: August 2019
- CitiSpire 6 Month Mentoring Program: December 2018 May 2019
- Digital Skills Training Program BuzzStart Academy in partnership with Facebook: May 2019
- UU Create Enterprise Program: April 2019
- UUSU Leadership Program Level 4 OCN in Leadership: March 2019
- UOTC Leadership in Practice: January 2019
- Belfast City Marathon Raised over £1,000 for Foyle Hospice & finished 9-mile walk: May 2019
- Essential First Aid Training John Ambulance: March 2019 March 2021
- Code First: Girls 8-week Web Development Course & Course Ambassador: October – December 2018
- Millennium Volunteer Award: September December 2014